# ÁLVARO PARADA

#### FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I'm a full stack developer with 2 years of experience, focused on clean code and best practices. My technical expertise lies in the MERN stack, primarily using TypeScript or JavaScript, and I prioritize testing to ensure the reliability and functionality of my applications. My engineering background brings a strong emphasis on collaboration, analytical thinking, and adaptability.

I am always eager for new opportunities to learn and grow, and I am open to new challenges in the industry.



**4** +34-615-928-718

alvaro.parada92@gmail.com



https://github.com/varitoapg

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/alvaro-parada/

# Education

### **Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp**

**ISDI** Coders jul. - dic. 2022

# Master's degree in Management **Engineering**

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya -**ESEIAAT** 

2018 - 2021

#### PLC programming

Centro de Investigación y Formación en Electricidad y Electrónica - CIFEE 2017 - 2018

# **Degree in Industrial Electronic Engineering and Automatic Control Systems**

Universidad de Cantabria - ETSIIT 2010 - 2017

# Skills

#### **Soft Skills**

Team player, Analytical thinking, Flexibility, High organizational skills, Learnability

#### **Technical Skills**

Typescript, Javascript, Python, Jest, Cypress, React, NextJs, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, NodeJS, Git, Github, MongoDb, MySQL, GraphQL, Figma, Agile

#### Languages

• Spanish(native) • English (B2)

# **Work Experience**

#### Full-stack developer

ESTOKO Logistics | April 2023 - now

- Contributed to the development of an innovative operational tool utilizing new technologies like PostgreSQL, Next.js, Apollo GraphQL and Prisma, focusing on frontend development while providing occasional backend support to ensure a well-rounded approach.
- Manteinance of many applications, prioritizing frontend optimization and user interface enhancements for a seamless user experience.
- Collaborated closely with the technical lead and project manager to ensure an efficient team coordination in an Agile methodology, maintaining a highly productive work environment.

#### **Full Stack developer**

Freelance | Sept. 2022 - Dic. 2022

- Developed SPAs using MERN stack, with Redux to manage global
- Worked with a team of full stack developers and a Tech Lead using agile management to build an app incorporating best practises.
- · Created integration and unit tests.

# **Junior Engineer**

OXIGEN Salud | Jun. 2022 - Sept. 2022

- · Continuously improved production process, while optimizing storage and production layouts.
- Stock and order control through Excel spreadsheets automatization.
- Improvement of web components.

# Quality and Logistic Engineer

SEUR GEOPOST | Feb. 2020 - Sept. 2020

- Developed and implemented a project about a logistic improvement of refrigerated deliveries temperature control.
- Created a new procedure for PDA's usage.
- Executed 5s methodology and fixed logistic problems.
- Improved stock control by automating spreadsheets.